teamviewer.com 2019-12-31

# TeamViewer Privacy Policy

## **TeamViewer Privacy Policy**

Updated December 17, 2019

### Introduction

We, the TeamViewer Group, take protection of your personal data very seriously. The following policy provides an overview of how we ensure this protection and what kind of data is processed for what purpose. Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, such as your name, address, email addresses, IP address or user behavior. Further to this Privacy Policy, please refer to our product privacy policies for detailed information concerning your use of the various products.

A. Controller  
B. Data protection officer  
C. Categories of data  
D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing  
E. Web analytics and remarketing applications  
F. Recipients  
G. Retention periods for personal data  
H. Social media plugins  
I. Integrated third-party service tools  
J. Statutory/contractual requirement  
K. Your rights

## A. Controller

TeamViewer Germany  GmbH (“ **TeamViewer** ”), Jahnstr. 30, 73037 Göppingen,  _[privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com)_ , is controller of your personal data pursuant to Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”).

## B. Data Protection Officer

TeamViewer appointed Mrs. Hauser as external data protection officer, who can be reached at _[privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com)_ , at [ _KHauser@intersoft-consulting.de_](mailto:KHauser@intersoft-consulting.de) or at intersoft consulting services AG, DSB TeamViewer, Dürer Str. 189, 50931 Cologne.

## C. Categories of Data

TeamViewer collects and processes different categories of personal data depending on your use of our services. The following sections outline the categories of data processed by category or used service.

### I. Use of TeamViewer’s website

#### 1\. Protocol data

When you visit the TeamViewer website we collect the following personal data transmitted by your server:

  * IP address
  * Date and time of the request
  * Time zone difference from Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)
  * Content of the request (specific site)
  * Access status / HTTP status code
  * Volume of data transmitted each time
  * Website from which the request comes
  * Browser software, including language and version
  * Operating system and its interface
  * The country of origin for the visitor

#### 2\. Cookies

Furthermore, when you visit our website, cookies are stored on your computer. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your hard disk in association with the browser you are using and through which specific information flows to TeamViewer. Cookies cannot initiate programs nor deliver viruses to your computer. They serve to make our service more user-friendly and effective. This website uses the different kinds of cookies set out in our [Cookies Policy](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/privacy-policy/?policy=cookies)

#### 3\. Web analytics, (re-)marketing tools, social media plugins, and third-party integrated services

TeamViewer uses web analytic applications and (re-)marketing tools (please refer to section E. below for further information), social media plugins (please refer to H. for further information), and third party integrated services (please refer to I. for further information). By and through these applications and tools, personal data as set out in this Privacy Policy are collected and may be combined with other personal data we collect from you (please refer to section C.VI.3. below for further information on such combinations).

### II. Contacting TeamViewer

When you contact TeamViewer (e.g. through an online contact form, chat functionality on our website or via phone), TeamViewer will collect **any personal information you submit, such as your first name, last name, email-address, country, job title, phone number, company information (including company size)** , **subject** , and **description of your query.** The collection of this data may be facilitated by third-party providers, which e.g. help us to provide particular landing pages and particular web forms (see below, section F.). We will use the collected information for contacting you and serving your request.

As a global company, we may receive messages that require translation of the content of some inquiries. In such case, our employees use third-party translation tools in order to process your inquiry. Thus, you might want to avoid entering personal information into the subject line and description field of your inquiry.

Please refer to the sections below for data collected and processed in specific cases of contacting TeamViewer, e.g. by submitting a ticket and requesting a quote.

### III. Submitting a ticket

If you submit a ticket for your TeamViewer product, TeamViewer will process your **email-address, license key and any additional information you submit** in connection with the ticket. This may include your **name, phone number, country, reason for submitting the ticket** , **log files compiling connection history, IP addresses, and information on your use of the TeamViewer product** collected through the SupportCollector tool, but we will inform you separately in each case about the data that is required to resolve your request.

### IV. Use of quote request feature

If you request a quote for one of our products, **TeamViewer will collect and process any information you submit, such as your salutation, first name, last name, address, email-address, company, phone number, country, and product inquiry.** We may also store some or all of that information in our customer relationship management system, which is facilitated by a third-party service provider (see below, section F.).

### V. Purchase of a fee-based license

If you purchase a fee-based license (e.g. through the “Buy Now” feature on our website), we will collect and process **any information you submit, such as salutation, your** **first name, last name, address, email-address, company, phone number, country, and your chosen payment method**. We will also process **information to support payment processing, including a** **payment token,** which is provided by our payment service provider as a record of the transaction. When issuing our invoice, corresponding data such as an **invoice ID** , **price paid, currency, invoice date,** and **tax code (e.g. VAT ID)** , will be collected and processed.

Once you have purchased a license, TeamViewer will create a corresponding **license key** and add it, together with information on your license’s **start and expiry dates** to your TeamViewer account, which you will be asked to create (please see our Product Privacy Policy, section C.III., for any data collected and processed when creating a TeamViewer account).

Where you have purchased a license through one of our partners (resellers or distributors), they will transfer personal data they have collected in the context of your purchase to TeamViewer. We will use this data to process your purchase and for continuously providing our services to you.

Data collected in the course of any purchase will be stored and further processed in our customer relationship management system, which is facilitated by a third-party service provider (see below, section F.).

We will use your email-address to provide you with our newsletter, which will inform you about products and services similar to the one you have purchased (see below, section VI.)

### VI. TeamViewer contacting and informing you (including marketing efforts, newsletter subscription, and profiling)

#### 1\. Newsletter and newsletter interaction tracking

If you sign up for our newsletter or purchase a license, TeamViewer will collect and process your **email-address** for the purpose of sending out our newsletter.

In our newsletters, we want to provide you with information which is most relevant and interesting for you. For this reason, we (facilitated by our data processor Inxmail GmbH) may track **reactions to and interactions with emails we send you** (e.g. whether you open the newsletter, click on the text and image links or display the images contained in the emails).

#### 2\. Other communications, including contacting you by email or phone and targeted advertising

We may use the contact information you provide in the course of activities described in C.II.-V. in order to get in touch with you. In this context, we may

  * contact you by email, beyond sending our regular newsletter (e.g. to send out promotional materials to you as our customer or to invite you to participate in customer satisfaction and other surveys as described below in section IX.), using the **email-address** you submitted, or by phone using the **phone number** you submitted (e.g. during, or in due course after expiry of a product trial you requested or to follow up on feedback or inquiries you have placed with us); or
  * conduct **targeted advertising** to inform you about changes to or improvements of our products, entirely new products, or to provide you with tips on how to best use our products as well as other useful information (e.g. on discounts, freebies or give-aways); we may do so on our websites, within our products and apps, or on third-party websites and apps.

#### 3\. Analyses on **personal** **data gathered from different sources, profiling**

We may combine

  * **the information you submit to us** (e.g. when contacting our sales and support teams, requesting a quote or providing feedback) and, more generally, your **interactions with our communication channels** (e.g. metadata of phone calls, such as which personalized number you have called at what time, or email correspondence with our sales and support teams or your history of submitting tickets and how they have been handled);
  * information on your **interactions with our products** (such as product usage data as described in section 1.C.III. of our Product Privacy Policy, and data on the types and frequency of connections you make);
  * certain **customer information** , such as **account information** and **purchase history** ; and/or
  * information on your **online usage behavior** gathered through **Google Analytics** as explained further below in section E. (please note that you may configure your browser settings to prevent cookie placements in order to avoid that your online usage behavior data is processed and combined with other personal data we collect and process),

and conduct various analyses on this data. Please refer to section D.VI.3. below to find out more about these analyses and why we perform them.

### VII. Community

If you click on the community link, you will be forwarded to the TeamViewer community website. If you want to join TeamViewer’s community, you have to sign in and/or sign up with your TeamViewer credentials, such as **your  email address, your name, and a password. **For providing TeamViewer’s community website, we cooperate with Lithium Technology, LLC (“ **Lithium** ”), which means that your personal data as described in C.I. will be processed by Lithium as data processor on TeamViewer’s behalf. For further information on how Lithium processes personal data, please refer to their privacy policy under  _<https://www.lithium.com/privacy>_. In TeamViewer’s community, you may comment on different subjects concerning TeamViewer’s activities and products. If you post a comment in TeamViewer’s community, we will store your **name/user name (depending on your choice), email-address, IP address, and any additional information you submit**. Further, we collect and process additional information on your comments, e.g. how many comments you post, how other members react to your comments or how valuable your comments are, including to give certain rewards to TeamViewer community members.

Your comment will be published in the relevant topic section by showing your user name as the author. Please note that your comments are publicly accessible and will appear in search engines. Therefore, please consider carefully what you post prior to posting your comment. Further, you may want to use an assumed name instead of your real name.

### VIII. Blog

TeamViewer will process your **email-address** if you subscribe to our blog.

If you post a comment in our blog on different subjects concerning TeamViewer’s activities and products in TeamViewer’s blog, TeamViewer will process your name/user name (depending on your choice), email-address and any additional information you submit. Your comment will be published in the relevant topic section by showing your user name as the author. Please note that your comments are publicly accessible and will appear in search engines. Therefore, please consider carefully what you post prior to posting, particularly if your comment contains personal data. Further, you may want to use an assumed name instead of your real name.

### IX. TeamViewer surveys

If you participate in a survey performed by or on behalf of TeamViewer, we collect and process your  **name,  email-address, **and **  user experience** as well as **any other personal information you submit** to us in the survey. In each survey, we may inform you separately about additional personal data collected and processed.

## D. Purpose and legal basis for processing

### I. Use of TeamViewer’s website

We want to ensure that when you visit any part of TeamViewer’s website, your journey will be user-friendly and particularly that you do not encounter technical problems and malfunctions. Also, we would like to make sure we provide you with the most relevant content on our website, which may require that we consider certain personal data such as your browser’s language settings or the country from where you visit our services. Legal basis for processing personal data described in C.I.1. is our legitimate interest, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

Regarding data collected and processed in the context of web analytics and (re-)marketing activities, please refer to relevant sections below (VI. and E.).

### II. Contacting TeamViewer

If you contact TeamViewer, we need to process your personal data in order to serve your inquiry. Legal basis for processing your personal data is your request prior to entering into a contract or our existing contractual relationship with you, i.e. Art. 6 para 1 lit. b) GDPR, or our legitimate interest, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

### III. Submitting a ticket ** **

If you submit a ticket that concerns one of our products, we will process your personal data to answer your inquiry. We use this feature to fulfil our business purpose to authenticate our product users and provide service resolution for our customers. Legal basis for such processing is our contractual relationship with you, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

### IV. Use of quote request feature

If you request a quote for our product, TeamViewer needs to process your personal data in order for us to properly respond to your request. Legal basis for processing your personal data is your request prior to entering into a contract, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

### V. Purchase of a fee-based license

If you use our website or any other means to purchase a fee-based license, TeamViewer needs to process your personal data for the performance of this transaction. Legal basis is therefore Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

### VI. TeamViewer contacting and informing you (including marketing efforts, newsletter subscription, and profiling)

#### 1\. Newsletter and newsletter interaction tracking

If you sign up for our newsletter, TeamViewer processes your personal data in order to send you the newsletter. If you have thus given us your consent, the legal basis for sending the newsletter to your email-address is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR. You may withdraw such consent at any time with effect for the future. Please use the unsubscribe link provided in each of the newsletter emails or contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

If you have purchased a license, we will subscribe you to our newsletter, which covers information about similar products to the one you purchased, on the basis of § 7 para. 3 of the German Unfair Competition Act (UWG) or other statutes implementing Art. 13 para. 2 of the E-Privacy Directive 2002/58/EC. In this case, you may object to receiving the newsletter at any time, and at no additional cost (beyond the basic cost of the means you use to communicate your objection) by using the unsubscribe link provided in each of the newsletter emails or contacting [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

Tracking your and others’ reactions to and interactions with our newsletters helps us to deliver the content most useful for you, and to analyze and evaluate the effectiveness of our marketing efforts.  We conduct such processing to fulfill our corresponding legitimate business interest pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit f) GDPR.

#### 2\. Other communications, including contacting you by email or phone and targeted advertising

All processing of personal data we use for contacting you and advertising towards you is based on either your explicit consent according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR or our legitimate business interest according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

When we contact you by email to convey marketing messages, we may also rely on § 7 para. 3 German Unfair Competition Act (UWG) or other statutes implementing Art. 13 para. 2 of the E-Privacy Directive 2002/58/EC as legal basis if you have previously purchased a license. You may opt-out of receiving such messages at any time, and at no additional cost (beyond the basic cost of the means you use to communicate your objection) by using the unsubscribe link provided in each of our emails.

#### 3\. Analyses on personal data from different sources, profiling

We strive to continuously improve the experience of using our website and our products and to inform you in the most relevant way possible. In order to do so, we aim to better understand and categorize the needs of our prospects, users, and customers. Through combining non-personal and personal data from different sources as described in section C.VI.3. above, by analyzing this data, and through corresponding profiling measures, we aim to determine the most suitable product offerings for certain groups of persons or for you individually, and thus ultimately to best serve any requests you have or may have with regard to TeamViewer or its products.

We conduct these analyses to help us decide on whether, when, and how to inform or get in touch with you. In this context, it is our aim to convey relevant information about our products also in the most suitable manner, which may include in-product messages (if you use any of our products; please refer to sections C.VII. and D.VII. of our Product Privacy Policy for further information), email communications or contact by phone.

Also, the analyses will assist us in predicting as well as retrospectively evaluating the effectiveness of our marketing and sales efforts.

To every extent possible, the described analyses and profiling measures will be based on pseudonymous data (e.g. we may consider the Google Analytics Client ID and other non-personalized cookie data, or data we have connected to your TeamViewer Device ID, rather than using immediately identifying personal data such as your name or email-address).

The legal bases for processing personal data for analysis and profiling purposes are performance of or processing prior to entering into a contract (e.g. when you contact our sales team and ask for a demo), i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR, and/or our legitimate interest (e.g. when we try to find out what information about our products you might be most interested in and whether and how to best get in touch with you), i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

Please get in touch with us at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com), in particular should you have any questions or if you would like to raise an objection against the described processing activities.

### VII. Community

TeamViewer’s community helps us to satisfy our business purpose to assist product users with an open platform, on which issues, experiences and improvements can be shared and resolved. Your personal data is being processed so we understand what topics are most relevant to our users and for us to design our website user-friendly and interesting. TeamViewer also processes your personal data so that we are able to raise a defense in the event that a third party complains about your community comment’s content. In such case, TeamViewer needs to be able to contact you. Any comments you post may also be analyzed by TeamViewer against the community terms of use, including for the purpose of rewarding certain actions of community users. Legal basis for such processing is a user agreement concerning the use of our community and our legitimate interest of incentivizing positive contributions to the community as well as possible legal defense, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) in connection with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

### VIII. Blog

TeamViewer’s blog helps us to satisfy our business purpose to assist product users with an open platform where issues, experiences and improvements can be shared and resolved. TeamViewer also processes your personal data so that we are able to raise a defense in the event that a third party complains about your blog comment’s content. In such case, TeamViewer needs to be able to contact you. Legal basis for such processing is our legitimate interest in possible legal defense, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

### IX. TeamViewer surveys

If you participate in TeamViewer surveys, we will process your personal data to analyze user experience and improve our knowledge. Legal basis is your consent, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit a) GDPR, which you may withdraw at any time with effect for the future.

### X. Other

Where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to, we process your personal data according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c) GDPR.

## E. Web analytics and (re-)marketing applications

### I. Tools to collect and process web analytics data, in particular use of Google Analytics

#### 1\. Google Analytics and other analysis tools provided by Google

TeamViewer uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon House, 4 Barrow Street, Dublin, Ireland, or any other Affiliate of Google LLC (“ **Google** “). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, i.e. text files that are stored on your computer and enable analysis of your use of our website. When you visit our website for the first time, you will be assigned a cookie with a unique user identification, i.e. a **Google Analytics Client ID**. We may replace this Google Analytics Client ID with your TeamViewer Device ID if you use one of our products (please refer to our Product Privacy Policy for details and to section C.VI.3 on the combination of data from various sources). We will add the respective data point to the data available in the Google Analytics tools, and this way we use Google Analytics also for cross-device analyses of user streams.

TeamViewer uses Google Analytics with the extension “_anonymizeIp()”. Thereby, IP addresses are processed in a shortened form. The information generated by cookies about your use of this website is usually transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the USA. Only in exceptional circumstances will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of the Google Analytics data collection will not be merged with other data from Google.

Other tools we use in this context that are also provided by Google include

  * **Google Tag Manager** (a tag management system that allows TeamViewer to quickly and easily update tracking codes and related code fragments collectively known as “tags” on our website or mobile app);
  * **Google Big Query (** an enterprise data warehouse that enables SQL queries using the processing power of Google’s infrastructure; TeamViewer uses Big Query to store and query data sets which are collected by Google services such as Google Analytics, and the Big Query data is used to build flexible reports for evaluating our website performance);
  * **Google Display Network** (used to measure the impact of unclicked Google Display Network ad impressions on the website, behavior of users, and conversions; please refer to <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/3105620> for further information); and
  * **Google Optimize** (for A/B testing, offering to analyze user behavior by showing slightly varied website contents to different user groups, depending on profile matching; thereby, TeamViewer analyzes its online services, improves its web offerings, and can create an interesting user journey).

TeamViewer uses data gathered through your Google Analytics Client ID as well as other data generated from Google’s web analytics applications in order to perform analyses of your interactions with our products, services, and websites. With the help of Google’s Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, we will receive analyses on our users’ age, gender, and interest categories (please refer to <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en> for further information). We strive to offer you tailored products and services that are best suited for your individual circumstances. To that end, Google provides us with insights and statistics that help us to make our online presence, our communications to you, and ultimately our products more interesting and relevant for you. Legal basis to conduct and use the results of these analyses is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

As further explained in our [Cookies Policy](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/privacy-policy/?policy=cookies), you may block cookies from being stored on your device, and consequently prevent the described analyses from being conducted, by adjusting the settings in your browser software; however, in such case, you may not be able to use all of the features and functionalities of our website. You can also block the collection of the data generated by the cookie and the data related to your use of the website (incl. your IP address) as well as the processing of this data by Google, by downloading and installing a browser plugin available from the following link:  _[http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)_.

Please visit the website _<https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en> _for an overview on Google’s approach on data protection for Google Analytics as well as their privacy policy:  _<https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>_.

#### 2\. Hotjar

TeamViewer uses Hotjar heatmaps, recordings, funnels, forms and polls, services provided by Hotjar Ltd. (“ **Hotjar** ”), St. Julian’s Business Center, Elia Zammit Street, St. Julians 1000, Malta. Hotjar provides an all-in-one analysis and feedback tool that reveals the online behaviors and feedback of a website’s visitors. It helps to improve websites’ user experience and performance. Its analysis tools allow TeamViewer to measure and observe user behavior on our website, while the feedback tool allows TeamViewer to obtain feedback.

Site visitors are assigned a unique user identifier, so that Hotjar can keep track of returning visitors. This way, no information by which individual persons could be directly identified is collected. When collecting data with recordings, Hotjar also has automated suppression features in place and data is suppressed client-side, in the visitor’s browser, meaning that corresponding personally identifiable information never reaches Hotjar servers.

Data collected using Hotjar is stored in Ireland, using Amazon Web Services infrastructure. The applicable data retention period is a maximum of 365 days.

We use Hotjar’s functionalities because they serve to fulfil our legitimate business interest in providing our website and improving upon it, the legal basis for processing your personal data is thus Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. To prevent us and Hotjar from collecting and processing your personal data, you may opt-out by following the instructions provided on Hotjar’s website <https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out>.

### II. (Re-)Marketing/retargeting applications

#### 1\. Google AdWords Conversion and Google Remarketing

TeamViewer’s website uses Google AdWords in order to generate attention for our products and services by conducting targeted advertising campaigns on third-party websites and apps. Data generated by such campaigns helps us to determine the success rate of individual campaigns. TeamViewer aims at providing you with advertisement that is of interest to you, to make its website more interesting, and calculate advertising expenses accurately. Legal basis for such processing of personal data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

Such means of advertisement are delivered by Google through a so-called Ad Server. Along with this, TeamViewer uses **Ad Server Cookies** , which scale certain parameters, such as display of ads or clicks by users. When you click on an ad delivered by Google that redirects you to our website, a cookie is stored on your computer by Google AdWords. These cookies usually expire within 30 days and are not supposed to be used to personally identify a user. In addition to these cookies, analytic values like a **unique cookie ID, quantity of Ad impressions per storing, last impression and opt-out information** (markings that the user does not want to be addressed any further) are usually stored. These cookies enable Google to recognize your internet browser.

If you visit certain pages on our website and provided the cookie stored on your computer has not yet expired, TeamViewer and Google are able to recognize that you clicked on an ad and were redirected to the TeamViewer website. Every Google AdWords customer receives a different cookie. Therefore, cookies cannot be tracked across different sites by TeamViewer, as is the case for all other AdWords customers. TeamViewer merely receives statistical evaluations from Google. By and through these statistical evaluations, we can evaluate which advertisement campaign was particularly effective. Any additional data generated by the particular advertisement is not forwarded to TeamViewer; particularly, we cannot personally identify users through this information.

Through this (re-)marketing tool, your browser automatically connects to Google’s servers. Please note that scope and further use of the data processed by Google are subject to Google’s privacy policy and beyond TeamViewer’s control. We thus inform you based on our own knowledge: By integrating AdWords, Google receives information that you visited a particular TeamViewer website or part thereof, and/or that you clicked on one of our advertisements. If you are registered with one of Google’s services, Google is able to match your visit to your Google account. Google may receive your IP address and/or may store it even if you are not registered with one of Google’s services and/or if you have not been logged in. You may avoid tracking in various ways, e.g. through

  * a setting of your browser software, particularly, by suppressing third party cookie installation in order to prevent receiving third-party ads;
  * deactivating AdWords Cookies, by setting your browser so that cookies from www.googleadservices.com are being blocked; this can be done at _<https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous>_ , however, such settings are deleted if you delete cookies; or
  * permanently deactivating cookies in your browser under <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996>.

Further information on Google’s approach to data privacy can be found under <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>. Alternatively, you can disable the use of cookies for interest-based advertising via the advertising network initiative, by following the instructions at  _<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>_.

In addition to Google AdWords, TeamViewer uses the tool “ **Google Remarketing** ”. This is an application that allows us to address you again, even when you have left our website. After visiting our website and while you are surfing the internet, our advertisement can be displayed to you by and through this application. This is enabled by cookies stored on your device, which track and analyze user behavior on different websites for Google. Google can track your previous visits to our website.

According to its own statement, Google does not combine data gathered through Remarketing with any personal data Google may have stored about you. Furthermore, the data processed for these purposes is generally limited to pseudonymous information. If you do not want to be exposed to data processing through the Google Remarketing feature, you can disable it by changing the appropriate settings at  _<https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous>_.

#### 2\. Social media tracking tools, including “tracking pixels”

We also use other tools on our website allowing us to offer you a more personalized and engaged web experience by offering you advertisements on your social media channels that are more relevant to you. To that end, we use cookie-based (please refer again to our [Cookies Policy](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/privacy-policy/?policy=cookies)) tools offered by the following third-party social media providers:

  2.     2.       * **Facebook Inc.** , 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA; for further information on the implemented tool, please refer to https://developers.facebook.com/docs/facebook-pixel/implementation#base-code; additional information on data collection:  _<https://www.facebook.com/help/186325668085084>_
      * **LinkedIn Corporation** , 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, California 94043, USA; for further information on the implemented tool and how to opt out of corresponding tracking, please refer to <https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out>; for further information on LinkedIn’s approach to privacy refer to:  _<https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=uno-reg-guest-home-privacy-policy>_
      * **Twitter Inc.** , 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, California 94103, USA; for further information on the implemented tool and how to opt out of corresponding tracking, please refer _to<https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads>_; for further information on Twitter’s approach to privacy refer to: <https://twitter.com/en/privacy>.

In each case, we integrate snippets of code provided by these social media operators that load a small library of functions (sometimes referred to as “tracking pixels”, i.e. transparent, pixel-sized images embedded in websites with a tracking functionality). These functions enable us to track your activities on our website, such as URLs visited, domains visited, device(s) used, and, in particular advertising conversions (i.e. actions counted when you interact with one of our ads, such as clicking it and purchasing our product afterwards). They rely on cookies placed by the mentioned third-party providers, which may also enable us to match our website visitors to respective user accounts on the respective social media platforms.

We may also use the “ **Custom Audience** ” service provided by Facebook Inc., for delivering targeted advertising to you. In this context, we would check whether you hold an account with Facebook for which you use the same email-address that you have provided to us and include you in a corresponding “custom audience” group. This works by us providing your email-address to Facebook Inc. in a hashed format, and this way making sure that Facebook will only process, as a data processor on our behalf, actual email-addresses of users that have already subscribed to their service (please refer to <https://www.facebook.com/business/help/112061095610075?helpref=faq_content> for further information on this process). You may opt-out of receiving targeted ads because you are part of a custom audience created by TeamViewer through clicking a corresponding link when you select the “Why am I seeing this?” feature on the Facebook platform (see <https://www.facebook.com/help/562973647153813?helpref=about_content>).

As with other marketing activities, the use of the described tracking and remarketing mechanisms fulfil our legitimate business interest pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Please take note of your options to opt-out of such tracking and remarketing mentioned above.

#### 3\. Other (re-)marketing tools used in certain regions

While we rely on services provided by Google for most regions targeted by our advertising campaigns, in certain regions we may additionally use other providers to fulfil essentially similar functions as described above for Google AdWords and Google Remarketing. These include

  2.     2.       * **Metrica** web analytics, a tool provided by Yandex Oy Limited Company, Moreenikatu 6, 04600 Mantsala, Finland, for situations where (i) it appears that your location is within the Russian Federation, (ii) you are visiting our Russian website, (iii) you were referred to our website by a search engine provided by Yandex; and (iv) you have not opted out of being tracked by Yandex.Metrica by installing a corresponding browser add-on (please refer to <https://yandex.com/support/metrica/general/opt-out.html> for further information);
      * **Baidu** , provided by Baidu, Inc., No. 58 North-West 4th Ring Road, 100080 Beijing, People’s republic of China, for situations where (i) it appears that your location is within the People’s Republic of China, (ii) you are visiting our Chinese website, and (iii) you were referred to our website by a search engine provided by Baidu;
      * **Naver,** 6 Buljeong-ro, Bundang-gu, Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do, Korea, for situations where (i) it appears that your location is within South Korea, (ii) you are visiting our Korean website, and (iii) you were referred to our website by a search engine provided by Naver;
      * **Yahoo Japan,** 1-3 Kioicho, Chiyoda-ku, Tokyo 102-8282, Japan, for situations where (i) it appears that your location is within Japan, (ii) you are visiting our Japanese website or service, and (iii) you were referred to our website by a search engine provided by Yahoo Japan.

Please note that you may opt-out of being tracking and thus prevent us from collecting corresponding data and providing you with personalized advertising by following the instructions given on the websites of the providers mentioned above, including on

  2.     2.       * <https://yandex.com/support/metrica/general/opt-out.html>;
      * <https://www.baidu.com/duty/safe_control.html>;
      * <https://about.yahoo.co.jp/docs/info/terms/privacyguide.html>;

or generally by adjusting your browser settings.

## F. Recipients

TeamViewer employees, who administer, maintain and further develop TeamViewer’s website, products and services will receive access to your personal data. To that end, TeamViewer has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure to third parties and to ensure that only relevant individuals, who act within their job description and have a need-to-know interest in accessing any of your personal data, will have access to the data for which they have sufficient clearance.

If you use our product, contact us through the contact, support, and feedback features, and/or if you request a quote, TeamViewer employees that are responsible for the respective service will receive access to your personal data. Aside from TeamViewer employees, your personal data may be processed by employees of third-party services providers, who assist us in handling your requests, e.g. if you use our chat functionality (e.g. Userlike UG), speak to us on the phone (e.g. we instruct call center agents from Competence Call Center Leipzig GmbH), or contact us through forms on certain website landing pages (e.g. employees of Unbounce Marketing Solutions Inc.).

If you post a comment in TeamViewer’s community or blog, your comment content and name/user name will be publicly available and may appear in search engines. Aside from TeamViewer employees, employees of Lithium may receive access to your personal data as described in C.VII.

If you purchase a TeamViewer product, TeamViewer employees concerned with processing such transactions will receive access to your data. We also use the services of third-party payment token providers.

TeamViewer may transfer your personal data to third parties if we offer participation in campaigns, contests, reservations, or contract agreements in conjunction with a third party. In this case, you will be specifically informed about the transmission to the third parties.

Also, many of our activities of providing you with information and marketing messages as well as analyzing (as described in section C.VI.) your reactions and interactions with TeamViewer and its products and communication channels are conducted by dedicated departments within TeamViewer, by using pseudonymous data (such as your TeamViewer Account ID, TeamViewer Device ID, hashed / abbreviated email-address or license key) to every extent possible. However, some data processing in this regard will be handled by third-party providers on our behalf. This includes MaTelSo GmbH for phone call (metadata) tracking and Inxmail GmbH for email communications, and Competence Call Center Leipzig GmbH for contacting you by phone.

For web analytics and (re-)marketing activities, we rely on a number of third-party providers, which will process personal data on our behalf as explained in more detail in section E.

Finally, TeamViewer uses external third-party service providers to help operate its business, such as providers of IT operation and maintenance services, (cloud) storage service providers and providers of (cloud) collaboration tools. Examples include Amazon Web Services, Box.com, and Microsoft (Dynamics 365, Azure).

All mentioned third-party providers and employees of such providers may receive access to personal data through the service they provide.

TeamViewer chooses all third-party service providers with due care, obligates them to confidentiality, and concludes data processing agreements with them in accordance with the standards of the GDPR. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

In addition, for the purpose of integrating the services described under -H. and I. into our website, employees of the providers of social plugins and integrated services, as described below, may receive access to your personal data. Please note that such data processing conducted by social plugin providers and integrated service providers is subject to those providers’ privacy policies and generally beyond TeamViewer’s control.

TeamViewer will generally not transfer your personal data outside the EU and/or EEA. However, there are some exceptions to this rule, which include data transfers (i) mentioned in section E., -(ii) to the USA, and (iii) for group internal IT services provided from outside the EU, including Australia, USA and Armenia. TeamViewer will otherwise transfer your personal data only when required to do so by law or in case of orders from a competent authority.

Whenever TeamViewer transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have an adequate level of data protection recognized by the EU, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. In particular, we will conclude model contracts with corresponding entities and rely on the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework for certain transfers into the USA. Please refer to <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en> to obtain further information on the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established outside the EU or EEA, or to  _<https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>_  to obtain further information on the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

We will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

## G. Retention periods for personal data

Your personal data will be deleted once you withdraw consent, or, more generally, once the purpose for processing has ceased to exist. In some cases, TeamViewer is legally obligated to retain data for a certain period. Once this period has lapsed, TeamViewer will delete the data in accordance with data protection obligations.

We may also use and embed in our website certain social media plugins (“ **plugins** ”) from third-party providers such as **Facebook** ,  **LinkedIn** , and  **Twitter**  (“ **plugin provider** ”).

Facebook’s plugins are identifiable by the Facebook logo and/or the “thumbs up” – symbol. Furthermore, TeamViewer may use the ”in” button from LinkedIn, which can be identified by a blue button. Additionally, TeamViewer may use the short messaging service Twitter, which can be identified by a button that contains a bird. You can find more information on these social media providers above at section E.II.2.

By using plugins, TeamViewer provides an opportunity to interact with social media and other social media users on its website. Plugins are provided to increase TeamViewer’s internet presence and make it more interesting to you. Legal basis for use of the plugins is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

Every time you visit our website and any part thereof that contains a plugin, the plugin causes your browser to directly connect with the plugin provider’s server.

By activating (clicking on the button) the plugin, personal data may be transmitted to and stored by the plugin provider, likely on a server in the USA. As personal data is collected by and through cookies, you may avoid corresponding data processing by adjusting your browser cookie settings. Please note that data collection and processing are subject to the plugin providers’ privacy policies and generally beyond TeamViewer’s control, and we have neither been informed of the entire scope of data collection, purpose of the processing, nor any data retention periods. We have also not been informed if and when data is being deleted.

Plugin providers store data collected about you as user profiles and use such data for advertisement purposes, market research and/or need based design of their websites. Evaluation of such data (even of users not logged in) is particularly used for need-based advertisements and to notify other users of the same social network of your activities on our website.

You have a right of objection concerning such user profiles, however, you have to address such objection to the respective plugin provider. In order to properly address your demand, we provide you with the relevant addresses:

  2.     2.       * **Facebook Inc.** , 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA;  _<https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>_ ; additional information on data collection:  _<https://www.facebook.com/help/186325668085084>_
      * **LinkedIn Corporation** , 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, California 94043, USA; for further information on LinkedIn’s privacy refer to:  _<https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=uno-reg-guest-home-privacy-policy>_.
      * **Twitter Inc.** , 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, California 94103, USA; for further information on Twitter’s privacy refer to:  _<https://twitter.com/en/privacy>_.

Your data is being transmitted to the plugin provider, regardless of whether you maintain a profile with the plugin provider and/or if you are currently logged in. If you are currently logged into your social media profile, data collected on your visit of our website is directly matched to your social media profile. If you activate the plugin, e.g. by liking or retweeting our website, such information is stored in your social media profile and will be publicly shared with your contacts.

### I. YouTube Videos

TeamViewer may integrate videos in its website, which are stored on <https://www.youtube.com/>. The YouTube platform is provided by YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA, an affiliate of Google. These videos can be played on our website.

When you visit a page on our website with embedded YouTube videos, YouTube receives information on what particular website you visit. Your personal data as described under C. is transmitted to YouTube. Such transmission takes place, regardless if you are logged into your Google account, or if you do not maintain such an account. If you are logged into your Google account, your personal data will be matched with your Google profile. If you do not wish that your personal data is being matched with your profile, you should log out of your YouTube account prior to activating a YouTube video. YouTube and Google will use your personal data for advertisement, market research, and/or need-based design of its website.

Please note that it is beyond TeamViewers control how long and in what way YouTube and Google will retain your data. For further information concerning purpose and scope of data collection and processing, please visit  _<https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>_.

You have a right to object to such processing of your personal data, but you will have to address such objection to YouTube or Google.

### II. reCAPTCHA

TeamViewer uses reCAPTCHA to protect our website from spam and abuse. reCAPTCHA is a service provided by Google that uses an advanced risk analysis engine and adaptive CAPTCHAs to keep automated software from engaging in abusive activities on our site.

reCAPTCHA allows TeamViewer to verify if an interaction is legitimate without any user interaction. It is a purely JavaScript API that returns a score giving us the ability to take action in the context of our website: for instance, requiring additional factors of authentication, sending a post to moderation, or throttling bots that may be scraping content.

Please note that scope and further use of the data processed by Google are subject to Google’s privacy policy and beyond TeamViewer’s control.

## J. Statutory/contractual requirement

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to use all of the functionalities of our website; where we ask for consent and you choose not to provide it, or you block, disable or delete cookies, we may not be able to provide you with the information or service requested.

## K. Your rights

You may contact us (e.g. under _[privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com),_ at 1-800-638-0253, or submit a ticket on our website) in order to exercise the following rights to the extent you are entitled to so under applicable law:

  2.     2.       * You may access your personal data to check and review such data;
      * You may request a copy of your personal data;
      * You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
      * You may object to the processing of your personal data;
      * You may request to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and – subject to your acquisition of the respective copyrights or other required rights – have it transmitted to another controller, provided that the processing is based on your respective consent or to execute a contractual relationship or a relationship prior to entering into a contract with you.
      * You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data. In order to file a complaint, please contact the supervisory authority competent for your place of residency or alternatively, you may contact “Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit, Königstraße 10a, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany“.

Your request will be promptly attended to by a member of our team. TeamViewer may request your name, email address, and/or account information in order to verify your request. Pursuant to the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”), you have a right to not receive discriminatory treatment for exercising your privacy rights. You may also designate an authorized agent to make a privacy request on your behalf.

TeamViewer does not sell your personal information to third parties, as that is defined under the CCPA.

Should you have any questions, please contact  _[privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com)_.

This Privacy Policy contains links to sites and information that are not under TeamViewer’s direct control. These links are therefore subject to change and TeamViewer will review and update this Privacy Policy periodically to reflect such changes.

## **TeamViewer Product Privacy Policy**

Updated December 17, 2019  
  
**Introduction**  
We, the TeamViewer Group, take protection of your personal data very seriously. Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, such as your name, address, email-addresses, IP address, or user behavior etc. The following policy provides you with information about the collection of personal data 1. in relation to the administration of the contractual relationship between you and TeamViewer Germany GmbH, and 2. your responsible use of the functionalities of our TeamViewer product, consisting of the Software as well as the Server Services as described and defined in the [End User License Agreement](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/eula/) (“ **EULA** ”) (hereinafter collectively referred to as (our) “ **Product** ”).

**1\. Personal Data collected and processed under control of TeamViewer**  
A. Controller  
B. Data protection officer  
C. Categories of data  
D. Purpose and legal basis for processing  
E. Recipients  
F. Retention periods for personal data  
G. Statutory/contractual requirement  
H. Automatic decision-making  
I. Your rights

**2\. Information concerning your responsible use of the Product**  
A. Personal data processed through your use of the Product  
B. Data usage  
C. Data subjects rights

## **1\. Personal Data collected and processed under control of TeamViewer**

### **A. Controller**

TeamViewer Germany GmbH (“ **TeamViewer** ”), Jahnstraße 30, 73037 Göppingen, is controller pursuant to Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”) concerning any processing of personal data for which we determine the purpose and means of processing. For information on data processing for which we act as a processor on your behalf pursuant to Art. 4 para. 8 GDPR, i.e. in relation to your responsible use of the functionalities of our Product as described in the EULA, please refer to section 2. below.

### **B. Data protection  officer**

TeamViewer appointed Mrs. Hauser as external data protection officer, who can be reached at _[privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com)_ , at [KHauser@intersoft-consulting.de](mailto:KHauser@intersoft-consulting.de) or at intersoft consulting services AG, DSB TeamViewer, Dürer Str. 189, 50931 Cologne.

### **C. Categories of data**

#### **I. Download, installation, and setup of the Product**

When you download a copy of the Software from our website, the Software will be marked with your associated **Google Analytics Client ID** in order to connect it to website usage data we collect. You may prevent such marking and subsequent analyses conducted by TeamViewer by taking measures (e.g. through your browser settings) for opting out of website tracking through Google Analytics. For further information on this category of data, including on the purpose of its collection and processing, please refer to our General Privacy Policy, sections C.VI., D.VI., and E.

When you install the Software and use the Product for the first time on a new device, we collect certain information from that device, such as your device’s MAC address, combined with other device-related information to ensure uniqueness. From this information, TeamViewer creates a unique **Machine ID** (MID), from which the TeamViewer master infrastructure generates the **TeamViewer Device ID** , which in turn allows it to distinguish between unique user devices that have the Software installed.

We will also ask you whether you use the Product (i) for private / non-commercial purposes, (ii) in a company / for commercial purposes, or (iii) for both, and your choice will be connected to the respective TeamViewer Device ID. We also collect and process information on the **type of license** (Freemium, trial, fee-based) under which you use the Product.

#### **II. Establishing a connection using the Product**

Whenever you run the TeamViewer Software client, the TeamViewer master server infrastructure will register whether the device is available for a connection session with other devices. To achieve that, TeamViewer collects and processes your **IP address, your location, TeamViewer Device ID, the Machine ID, and your chosen user screen name.** While trying to connect to another device, this data is exchanged between the TeamViewer master server infrastructure, selected TeamViewer routers, and the Software client of your envisaged connection partner. The decision on which connection paths are used, in particular which routing servers, depends on the analysis of this data, considering e.g. geography and current work load on individual routers. Once you successfully connect to another device and thus establish a remote control or other session with your connection partner, certain **Session Metadata** such as a **Session ID** , a **meeting ID,** and **the start and end times of your session** will be collected and processed.

#### **III. Signing up for a TeamViewer account**

When you sign up for a TeamViewer account, TeamViewer collects your  **name, email-address, a  password of your choice, along with time, date and time zone** of you signing in and creates a unique **TeamViewer Account ID** for your TeamViewer account.

#### **IV. Product usage data**

We collect and process information about **how you use  the Software and the Server Services**. This includes the **Session Metadata** mentioned above at 1.C.II., your **connection partners, which features of our Product you use** (including Remote Control, Chat, Video, and File Transfer), and **how frequently** you use them.

We may analyze this data together with information you submit to us, as further described under 1.D.IV. below as well as in our General Privacy Policy under sections C.VI.3. and D.VI.3.

#### **V. License auditing**

If you are using our Product under a Freemium Software license, we will analyze your **Product usage data** (see above 1.C.IV.) in accordance with section A./B.3.9 of the EULA to assess whether your usage pattern is in line with your indicated usage purpose and thus with the chosen license type. This assessment, which may also include an analysis of the **domain of an email-address** you have provided in the course of signing up for a TeamViewer account (see above!., will result in a “ **commercial score** ”. Depending on this score, we might suspect that a fee-based license, as opposed to a Freemium Software license, is required for your usage pattern of our Product, and we will inform you accordingly.

If you continue to use our Product in a way that indicates a violation of sections A./B.3.4 (Scope of use for the Freemium Software) and A./B.3.5 (Unauthorized Use) of the EULA, we may limit or ultimately block your access to the Server Services and ask you to purchase a fee-based license. In certain cases, this may involve an **automatic decision-making process** , where TeamViewer systems are configured to automatically put in place a limitation or even a blocking of your use of the Product.

If you think you are using our Product within the scope of the Freemium Software license, you may submit a corresponding request by way of our online form, for which we ask you to submit **your name, email-address, affected TeamViewer Device ID, and an explanation on your usage**. TeamViewer will then analyze your submission and again evaluate your detected usage patterns. In the course of the evaluation process, we may also ask you to submit a declaration confirming your use of our Product for private, non-commercial purposes only. For this declaration, we may ask you to submit **your name, postal address, explanation of your usage, and your signature**.

If you have indicated, at least partly, commercial purposes when installing the Software (see above, 1.C.III.) and do not decide to purchase a fee-based license after your free trial period expires, you may still want to continue using our Product as a Freemium Software user. In this case, you have to verify that you will be using our Product for private, non-commercial purposes only, by submitting your **TeamViewer Device ID, email-address, country, a description of your use of the Product, and log files from your device**. TeamViewer will analyze this information to determine whether the Freemium Software license is the correct license type for you.

#### **VI. Feedback**

When you provide feedback concerning your experience when using our Product, TeamViewer will collect and process **your TeamViewer Account ID (if you provide the feedback while logged-in), your country and language settings, as well as any information you submit in your inquiry (including attachments such as log files or screen shots), which may contain your email-address,  your name, company information, phone number, license key, or your TeamViewer Device ID.**

#### **VII. Support**

When you contact our support, we will collect your  **name, time and  date of your request, and your email-address**, if you contacted us via email, **or your  telephone number **if you contacted us via telephone, as well as the content of your request.

#### **VIII. Sending in-product messages**

TeamViewer may contact and inform you through in-product messages (using your **TeamViewer Device ID and, if you are a registered user, your TeamViewer Account ID** ) about changes to or improvements of our products, entirely new products, or to provide you with tips on how to best use our products as well as other useful information (e.g. on discounts, freebies or giveaways). In determining whether and how we contact and inform you, we may also process your **license type, language and version of the Product you use** , and/or your **country** , and we may also draw on data we have gathered through analyses and profiling measures as described in sections C.VI.  and D.VI. of our General Privacy Policy.

### **D. Purpose and legal  basis for processing**

#### **I.  ** **Download, installation, and setup of the Product**

When you install and setup our Product, TeamViewer processes your personal data to provide you with the option to use its functionalities. Legal basis to process your personal data as described under 1.C.I. is performance of our contract with you (i.e. the EULA) and thus Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

Regarding information on the purpose of marking your download copy of the Software with your Google Analytics Client ID, please refer to our General Privacy Policy, at sections D.VI.3.

#### **II. Establishing a connection using the Product**

Processing your personal data as described under 1.C.II. is necessary to provide you with the connection functionalities of our Product and thus to perform our contract with you (i.e. the EULA). The applicable legal basis is thus Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

#### **III. Signing up for a TeamViewer account**

When you sign up for a TeamViewer account, TeamViewer processes your personal data for the administration of the contract with you and to provide you with additional product functionalities. The legal basis to process your personal data as described under 1.C.III. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

#### **IV. Product usage data**

We strive to continuously improve the experience of using our Product. In order to do so, we need to better understand and categorize the needs of you, our users and customers. To achieve this, we may analyze how you use our Product as described under 1.C.IV. This way, we gather information that is required to improve and further develop our Product, e.g. to help us decide whether we should keep or amend functionalities the Product currently has or whether to create new features. We also evaluate your usage of the Product in order to recognize abusive or abnormal usage patterns and thus to help protect our network and service integrity at any time. Analyzing this information in this way is necessary to either perform our contract with you (i.e. the EULA) in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR and/or to fulfil our legitimate business interests pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

For more information on other purposes we also fulfil by processing Product usage data, namely to conduct license auditing and to gather information on whether and how to best contact and inform you, please refer to the respective sections below (1.D.V.) and in our General Privacy Policy (there at section D.VI.3.).

#### **V. License auditing**

TeamViewer processes information on how you use its Product in order to monitor and evaluate whether the agreed license restrictions are observed. Please note that, especially given the great number of (free) users of the Product, automated mechanisms such as limitations and ultimately blocking of suspicious usage are necessary to effectively monitor and enforce compliance with the licensing provisions of the EULA. Especially as the Freemium Software model is subsidized by the contributions of fee-based license customers, we have to make sure that everybody is using their licenses within the contractually agreed scope. Legal basis for processing your personal data as described under 1.C.V. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR and Art. 22 para. 2 lit. a) GDPR.

#### **VI. Feedback**

If you place an inquiry with TeamViewer by using the in-product feedback feature, TeamViewer processes your personal data in order to evaluate and possibly respond to your feedback. Legal basis for processing your personal data as described under 1.C.IV. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) and f) GDPR.

#### **VII. Support**

If you contact our support, TeamViewer processes your personal data in order to respond to your request. Legal basis for processing your personal data as described under 1.C.VII. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

#### **VIII. Sending in-product messages**

The data we process in order to decide whether and how to contact and inform you through in-product messages is required to perform our contract with you if you are using the Product under a Freemium Software license. Pursuant to section A./B.17. of the EULA, display and receipt of personalized marketing messages in the Software as well as the processing of personal data necessary to provide such personalization is a key element of our Freemium Software Product. The legal basis is thus Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

If you are using the Product under a fee-based license (other than Freemium Software), we will contact and inform you by way of in-product messages about our products and how you can use them most efficiently in order to meet our corresponding legitimate business interest. The legal basis is thus Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. You may choose to opt-out of receiving such messages by contacting privacy@teamviewer.com.

#### **IX. Other**

Where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to, we process your personal data pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c) GDPR.

### **E. Recipients**

TeamViewer has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure to third parties and to ensure that only relevant individuals, which act within their job description and have a need-to-know interest in accessing any of your personal data, will have access to the data for which they have sufficient clearance. This means, for example, that TeamViewer employees who conduct exercises of analyzing your usage behavior will, as a general rule, only receive pseudonymous data such as e.g. your TeamViewer Device ID, TeamViewer Account ID, or Session ID, rather than any data identifying you directly, such as your name or email-address. On the other hand, TeamViewer employees who administer and enhance the contractual relationship with you, will receive access to data identifying you by name, but will not necessarily gain access to profiling data.

We also use third-party service providers to help us operate our business and provide you the with the functionalities of our Product and serving your requests. This includes providers of connection routing services or IT operation and maintenance services, (cloud) storage service providers, and providers of (cloud) collaboration tools. These third-party providers may receive access to personal data through the service they provide. Examples include Anexia Internetdienstleistungs GmbH, Amazon Web Services, Box.com, or Microsoft (Dynamics 365, Azure).

TeamViewer chooses all third-party service providers with due care, obligates them to confidentiality, and concludes data processing agreements with them in accordance with the standards of the GDPR. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

Where TeamViewer transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have an adequate level of data protection recognized by the EU, for example to receive group internal IT services from Australia, the USA, and Armenia, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. In particular, we will conclude model contracts with corresponding entities and rely on the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework for certain transfers into the USA. Please refer to <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en> to obtain further information on the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established outside the EU or EEA, or to <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework> to obtain further information on the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

TeamViewer will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

### **F. Retention periods for personal  data**

TeamViewer retains your personal data for as long as is necessary according to the relevant legal basis for its processing. The exact retention period will thus depend on the categories of personal data and the processing purposes. Once this period has lapsed and a purpose for processing the data no longer exists, TeamViewer will delete the data.

### **G. Statutory/contractual requirement**

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to engage in a contractual relationship with us or receive adequate support.

### **H. Automatic decision-making**

Except as mentioned in 1.C.V. and 1.D.V. (License auditing), TeamViewer does not use your personal data for automatic decision-making that would produce legal effects or significantly affect you.

### **I. Your rights**

You may contact us in writing, by email at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com), toll-free at 1-800-638-0253, or on our websie at https://www.teamviewer.com/en/support/ in order to exercise the following rights to the extent you are entitled to do so under applicable law:

  * You may access your personal data to check and review such data;
  * You may request a copy of your personal data;  
You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
  * You may object to the processing of your personal data (e.g. if we base our processing on legitimate interests (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR) or use your personal data for direct marketing purposes);
  * You may request to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and – subject to your acquisition of the respective copyrights or other required rights – have it transmitted to another controller, provided that the processing is based on your respective consent or to execute a contractual relationship or a relationship prior to entering into a contract with you.
  * You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data. In order to file a complaint, please contact the supervisory authority competent for your place of residency or alternatively, you may contact “Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit, Königstraße 10a, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany“.

Please have your valid licensed TeamViewer account credentials ready in order for us to verify your request. Your request will be promptly attended to by a member of our team. Pursuant to the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”), you have a right to not receive discriminatory treatment for exercising your privacy rights. You may also designate an authorized agent to make a privacy request on your behalf.

TeamViewer does not sell your personal information to third parties, as that is defined under the CCPA.

Should you have any questions, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

### **2\. Information concerning your responsible use of the Product**

When you use our Product, we are providing it to you as a technical service that you may reasonably use. We technically assist you, as a data processor pursuant to Art. 4 para. 8 GDPR, with connecting to other devices, initiating meetings, the hosting of the contacts that you upload, or managing a team of people using our Product under your license. You are responsible for utilizing the Product in accordance with the applicable laws, including data protection laws. The particularities of tconchis relationship are defined in the [EULA](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/eula/), in particular in its section C. The following section of this Privacy Policy provides some additional explanations on how the Product works and what data is processed in this context on your behalf.

### **A. Personal data processed through your use of the Product**

In the following, we describe instances in which we are processing certain categories of personal data on your behalf when you use our Product.

#### **I.  Content data**

Any **content of screens, calls, and video transmissions, or actual files** that you exchange with anybody through our Product’s features and functionalities will be transmitted by TeamViewer using end-to-end encryption technology. This means that TeamViewer will not be aware of the content and subject matter of such exchanges. You, on the other hand, will have full access to this possibly personal and even sensitive data.

Our Product offers you the option to **share your screen** via the presentation, video call or phone call option. When you share your screen, please bear in mind that participants can see all items on your desktop.

The Product’s meeting functionality also enables you to be seen by other participants through your built-in device camera.

It is your responsibility to ensure that no rights of others are being infringed upon when such exchanges are initiated and conducted by you. Please bear this in mind, particularly when sharing information relating to persons not immediately involved in any current connection established through our Product (e.g. sensitive personal data on your device or the device of your connection partner that does not relate to either you or your connection partner).

#### **II. Scheduling and conducting a meeting**

While the content of any remote control sessions or meetings (such as presentations, video calls, and Voice over IP phone calls) will be transferred in an end-to-end-encrypted manner and thus generally not be visible for TeamViewer, we will still receive some metadata regarding your session such as any **meeting names** you use. If you use the “schedule meeting” function, TeamViewer processes additional personal data such as the  **subject of a meeting, time  **and, if you choose this option, **a meeting  password**.

#### **III. Log sessions reporting**

Our Product’s connection reporting feature will help you log and store connection metadata, including the **IP address, display name** and **  TeamViewer Device ID** for your connection partners. The log files including this personal data will be stored locally, i.e. on your device, and you can find the relevant path to the file through a link in the TeamViewer Software client. You may choose to deactivate this functionality, which is activated by default, by changing the options and preferences in the TeamViewer Software client.

#### **IV.  Session Recordings**

Our Product also gives you the option to **record and store content data** (see above 2.A.I.) in a location defined by you, such as a local or networked storage device. The Product will generally inform your session partners that a recording is being made and ask for their consent. Again, please make sure that such recordings do not infringe any rights of others.

#### **V.  Account data**

Our Product gives you the opportunity to store and share certain information within your TeamViewer account, such as your **email address** , a **user name** as well as a **display name** , your **language preferences** and **location**. You may also choose to edit your profile and upload a  **profile picture**. If you choose to upload a picture of yourself, please bear in mind that such picture is visible to your TeamViewer contacts. Please be aware that pictures may reveal your ethnic origin or health data, or may serve as biometric identifier, and consider the sensitivity of such data.

#### **VI.  ** **Buddy list, contacts**

Within your TeamViewer account, you may also create a **buddy list** containing information on **contacts** of yours. Please be mindful that contacts saved may contain data relating to persons who may not be aware that you saved them.

#### **VII. Data about employees or others using the Product under your license**

TeamViewer, as a data processor, will enable you to log and monitor connections and other activities conducted by employees or other persons using the Product under your license, in particular with regard to **account activities, recordings of sessions or connection metadata such as counterparts, start and end times, screen names** , etc. In your TeamViewer Management Console, you can activate and deactivate this feature and thus the described data processing for some or all of the accounts that are connected to your license, and you will be responsible for using these features in accordance with applicable laws, in particular data protection laws.

### **B. Data usage**

TeamViewer is using all of the personal data described in 2.A. above in order to provide you the functionalities of the Product as agreed in the EULA and the Order, and in accordance with the data processing provisions in the EULA, where additional information on security measures is available.

### **C. Data subjects rights**

Data subjects may exercise certain rights in relation to the processing of their personal data through the Product towards you. As your technical service provider, we may assist you to answer such requests as described in the data processing agreement in section C. of the EULA. Such rights may include accessing personal data, rectification, erasure, restriction of processing, data portability, and objection to the processing. Data subjects have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of their personal data.

Should you have any questions on the processing of personal data through TeamViewer, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

## **TeamViewer IoT Product Privacy Policy**

**Introduction**  
We at TeamViewer Germany GmbH take protection of your personal data very seriously. Personal data means any information that can personally reference you, such as your name, address, email addresses, IP address, etc. The following policy provides you with information about the collection of personal data 1. in relation to the administration of the contractual relationship between you and TeamViewer Germany GmbH, and 2. your responsible use of the functionalities of IoT, consisting of the TeamViewer IoT Monitoring and TeamViewer IoT Remote Control as well as the Server Services described in the EULA (hereinafter collectively referred to as “ **IoT** “).

**1\. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with TeamViewer**  
A. Controller respectively Provider  
B. Data Protection Officer  
C. Categories of Data  
D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing  
E. Recipients  
F. Retention Periods for Personal Data  
G. Statutory/contractual requirement  
H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling  
I. Your Rights

**2\. Information concerning your responsible use of IoT**  
A. Personal Data processed through your use of IoT  
B. Data Usage  
C. Data Subjects Rights

## **1\. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with TeamViewer**

### **A. Controller respectively Provider**

TeamViewer Germany GmbH, Jahnstraße 30, 73037 Göppingen (“ **TeamViewer”), is your contractual partner and controller of your personal data in accordance with Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR**** ”) and § 13 German Telemedia Act _concerning the entering into and administering the contractual relationship with you_. For information on data processing in relation to your responsible use of the functionalities of IoT as well as the Server Services as described in the EULA please refer to the information concerning the use of TeamViewer.

### **B. Data Protection Officer**

TeamViewer appointed Mrs. Hauser as external data protection officer, who can be reached at _[privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com)_ , at [KHauser@intersoft-consulting.de](mailto:KHauser@intersoft-consulting.de) or at intersoft consulting services AG, DSB TeamViewer, Dürer Str. 189, 50931 Cologne.

### **C. Categories of Data**

**I. Download IoT: When you download IoT to your computer, TeamViewer collects your **IP address** and **name****.

**II. Sign Up: Your **full name, address, user name, password, email address, time, date, time zone** and **bank information**** when you first sign up to use IoT, and in particular your email address for IoT to provide you with notifications and alerts.

**III. Protocol and Usage Data: We collect personal data transmitted through your browser, such as your **IP address** , **date** and **time of request** , **time zone differences** to Greenwhich Mean Time (GMT), **content of request** (specific site), **access status / HTTP status code, volume of data transmitted each time, website from which the request comes, browser, operating system** and its interface, **language and version of browser software, user’s country of origin**. Additionally, we processes your **user name** and **password**** , which are linked to your user profile. We collect information about your use of IoT.

**IV. License Auditing: We will collect information about the **frequency of your use**** of IoT and the Server Services.

### **D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing**

**I. Download:** When you download IoT, TeamViewer processes your personal data to provide you with the option to use IoT. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined above under C. I. is a user agreement concerning the use of IoT, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

**II. Signing up for TeamViewer:** When you sign up to IoT, TeamViewer uses your personal data for the administration and enhancement of the contract with you. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined under C. II. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

**III. Protocol and Usage Data:** When you log into TeamViewer IoT, we process your personal data so that a log in is successful and you do not encounter technical problems. We may process the usage data to improve functionalities of our IoT service. Legal basis for such processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) and Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

**IV. License Auditing:** TeamViewer is using information about the frequency of your use of IoT in order to monitor if the agreed license restrictions are observed and in case we recognize that they are exceeded, we will contact you to suggest changing your license type. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. III is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR.

### **E. Recipients**

TeamViewer has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure and to ensure that only relevant individuals, which act within their job description and have a need to know interest in accessing personal data, will have access to your personal data. TeamViewer employees, who administer and enhance the contractual relationship with you will receive access to your personal data. If you have a paid subscription, employees who are concerned with processing such transactions will receive access to your data. In case you contact our support, our employees who are engaged in providing support will handle your personal data to the extent required to answer your request.

However, we also instruct third parties, such IT maintenance and storage service provider, to help us to operate our business. These third party providers may receive access to personal data through the service they provide. TeamViewer has chosen these third parties with due care and obligated them to confidentiality. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

We will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

Where TeamViewer transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have an adequate level of data protection recognized by the EU, for example to receive group internal IT services from Australia, US and Armenia, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. Please refer to [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN) to obtain a copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established in third countries under Directive 95/46/EC, or to <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework> to obtain a copy of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

In the context of the provision of IoT, employees of TeamViewer’s affiliate Monitis LLC, located in Armenia (address: 9 Alek Manukyan St, Yerevan 0070, Armenia), may also have access to certain metadata and to data about the usage of the TeamViewer IoT for the purpose of performing analysis to improve and develop the TeamViewer IoT. Furthermore, employees from Monitis LLC may, in limited cases, provide you with support and thus receive access to your personal data. Additionally, employees of Hotjar Ltd, St Julians Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St Julians STJ 1000, Malta, may receive your personal data to analyze user behavior of IoT users.

### **F. Retention Periods for Personal Data**

TeamViewer retains your personal data for the duration of our contractual relationship with you, regardless if your subscription is for free or paid. Once this contractual relationship terminates, TeamViewer will delete your personal data, unless TeamViewer is legally obligated to retain personal data such as your name, your order form, and the date of the order, in accordance with § 257 German Commercial Code and/or § 147 German Tax Code for a minimum of six and a maximum of ten years, if you payed for TeamViewer. Personal data that we collect in order to carry out license auditing will be deleted three (3) months after the defined license auditing period has elapsed.

### **G. Statutory/contractual requirement**

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to engage in a contractual relationship with us or receive adequate support.

### **H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling**

TeamViewer does not use your personal data for automatic decision-making and profiling.

### **I. Your Rights**

You may contact us either in writing or by email at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com) in order to exercise the following rights to the extent your entitled to so under applicable law:

  * You may access your personal data to check and review such data;
  * You may request a copy of your personal data;
  * You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
  * You may object to the processing of your personal data;
  * You may request to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and – subject to your acquisition of the respective copyrights or other required rights – have it transmitted to another controller, provided that the processing is based on your respective consent or to execute a contractual relationship or a relationship prior to entering into a contract with you.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data. In order to file a complaint, please contact the supervisory authority competent for your place of residency or alternatively, you may contact “Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit, Königstraße 10a, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany“.

Should you have any questions on the processing of your personal data by TeamViewer in relation to your contractual relationship, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

## **2\. Information concerning your responsible use of IoT**

When you use IoT, we are providing the product to you as a technical service that you may reasonably use. We technically assist you, as a processor, with the use of the platform for your IoT decives. You are responsible for utilizing TeamViewer in accordance with the applicable laws, including data protection laws. The following section explains to you how IoT works.

### **A. Personal Data processed through your use of IoT**

When you use IoT, we receive information such as the **amount of devices connected through IoT, **log in time and date, functionalities used** and **metrics**** entered while you use IoT. Depending on the metrics defined by you in the IoT (the so-called metadata), we also receive data from devices that you connect with IoT (e.g. the temperature of a device or other metrics, as defined by you). While generally such kind of data in and of itself typically includes no personal data, we cannot exclude that you collect information that – either in itself or in connection with additional information – may be linked to individual persons (e.g. maintenance staff for an IoT device). It is therefore your responsibility to ensure that data collection through your IoT devices is fair, transparent and in line with applicable data protection laws.

### **B. Data Usage**

TeamViewer is using all of the personal data described in section II. A. in order to provide you with the functionalities of IoT as agreed in the End User License Agreement and the Performance Specification and in accordance with the data processing provisions in section C. of the End User License Agreement where additional information on security measures is available. To improve IoT’s functionalities, TeamViewer uses Hotjar to assist with the diagnosis of technical problems and to analyze user behavior trends. Hotjar is a software as a service tracking tool offered by Hotjar limited, Level 2, St. Julian’s Business Center, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St. Julians, Malta. Hotjar is only activated from time to time, mostly when updates are released. Hotjar collects information about the device that is used to log in to the TeamViewer IoT, such as the device’s IP address (captured and stored in an anonymized format); device screen resolution; device type (unique device identifiers), operating system, and browser type, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display the Hotjar enabled site, mouse events (movements, location and clicks), keypressers, referring URL and domain, pages visited, geographic location (country only), date and time of access. The sole purpose of collecting this data is to improve the functionality of IoT. TeamViewer does not store the data collected through Hotjar for longer than 24 hours and masks the user’s private information. The user can object to the use of Hotjar here: <https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out/> and can learn about Hotjar’s ability to use and share information through the Hotjar Terms & Conditions of Use, available at <https://www.hotjar.com/terms/>, and the Hotjar Privacy Policy, available at <https://www.hotjar.com/privacy/>.

We will not share personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

### **C. Data Subjects Rights**

Data subjects may exercise certain rights in relation to the processing of their personal data through TeamViewer towards you. As your technical service provider we may assist you to answer such request as described in the data processing agreement in section C of the End User License Agreement. Such rights might be accessing personal data, rectification, erasure, restriction of processing, data portability and objection to the processing. Data subjects have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of their personal data.

Should you have any questions on the processing of personal data through TeamViewer, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

## **TeamViewer Cookie Policy**

  * ### **I. Introduction**

TeamViewer Germany GmbH (“ **TeamViewer** ”) as an operator of this website strives to be clear and transparent about any data that we collect and process from and about you and how we do so. In the following policy, we elaborate how we use so-called “cookies”, pixels and similar technology, (together, the “ **Cookies** ”), their business purpose and how they allow us to improve our service and run our business. It also tells you how you can manage or delete the Cookies that are stored on your device or turn off the use of Cookies altogether. Furthermore, you can find more information about our use of Cookies in sections C., E. and H. of our Privacy Policy.

TeamViewer Germany GmbH is responsible for the cookies set on the website at www.teamviewer.com, except for the cookies in relation with the sub-page Investor Relations (“ **IR** ”). For the cookies set on the IR sub-page, TeamViewer AG is responsible. For more details, please refer to Annex 1 below.

  * ### **II. What are Cookies?**

Cookies are small text files containing information related to your internet settings, which are downloaded by your browser to the device you use when you visit our website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website (first-party Cookies) on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognizes that Cookie (third-party Cookies). Cookies perform a variety of useful jobs, such as remembering your preferences, adapting the content that you see and improving your online experience.

  * ### **III. When does TeamViewer place Cookies?**

TeamViewer uses Cookies on our website (such as teamviewer.com, Blizz.com, and TeamViewerIOT.com) and mobile applications. Any device with which you are visiting these websites will receive at least some Cookies from us, depending on the consent that you give us when first visiting our website or changing your Cookie preferences at a later stage.

  * ### **IV. How does TeamViewer place Cookies?**

When you visit our websites (through any device) for the first time, we will ask you to choose your preferences through our Cookie banner (“ **Banner** ”). Within the Banner you can make a choice according to your wishes, either allowing us to set certain or all Cookie categories, limiting the setting of the Cookies or not allowing any at all. We will place Cookies on your device based on your choice. Please note, however, that some Cookies will always be active, and we do not ask for your consent for these. This is true for the strictly necessary Cookies, because – as their name suggests – we need to place them for the proper functioning of our website (see also _Strictly Necessary Cookies_ section below).

You can change your preferences at any time in our Cookie Settings.

We may update our Cookie Policy from time to time, in particular to include or remove existing Cookies over time. Any such changes will be updated here or in our [Privacy Policy](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/privacy-policy/#teamviewer-website-privacy-policy).

  * ### **V. What types of Cookies are being used?**

    * #### **a. Different types regarding the provider of the Cookie**

TeamViewer uses both first- and third-party Cookies. First party Cookies are those set by TeamViewer itself. All other Cookies are third party Cookies, from companies such as Google Analytics, Facebook, Hubspot, LinkedIn etc. In some cases, the information derived from these Cookies may allow us to associate information with an identifiable individual, i.e. personal data (please also see below section VI.).

    * #### **b. Different types regarding the duration of storage**

      * ##### **i. Session Cookies**

Session Cookies last only for the duration of your visit of our website and are deleted when you close your browser. These help us to identify that a user of a particular device is navigating from page to page, supporting website security or basic functionality.

Many of the Cookies we use are session Cookies. For example, they help us to measure the average time you spend on our website.

      * ##### **ii. Persistent Cookies**

Persistent Cookies continue to exist even after you have closed your browser and allow a website to remember your actions and preferences, particularly remember you as an existing user. Sometimes persistent Cookies are used by websites to provide targeted advertising based upon the browsing history of the device.

TeamViewer uses persistent Cookies in a few ways, for example to distinguish users of our website and/or our products.

    * #### **c. Different types regarding the purpose of use**

Both session as well as persistent Cookies can serve different purposes and may be placed either by TeamViewer or by a third party. We differentiate between _strictly necessary Cookies_ , _performance Cookies_ , _functional Cookies_ , and _marketing and targeting Cookies_.

      * ##### **i. Strictly necessary Cookies**

These Cookies are essential in order to enable us to provide you with basic and security features of our website. Without these Cookies, certain services you have asked for cannot be provided, such as the use of areas of our website that are restricted to registered users (a Cookie, which identifies registered users to recognize them throughout the visit and upon return, e.g. within the login area of our Management Console) and webshop related services. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request for services, such as setting your privacy preferences, logging in or filling in forms. These Cookies are not implemented to gather information about you for other purposes such as marketing or analytics. Please refer to the full list of Cookies that TeamViewer uses for more information in **Annex 1**.

      * ##### **ii. Performance cookies**

These Cookies are used to collect information about the performance of our website and your visit and use of our website, for example, the number of visitors that used our website and the pages that are popular among our visitors. These Cookies do not collect information that directly identifies a visitor, although they may collect the IP address of the device used to access the site. Such information is used for the purpose of improving our website and the general user experience. Without the performance Cookies we will not be able to improve our website and its functionalities to provide you with the best surfing experience. If you do not allow these Cookies, your visit to our site will not be counted, which will negatively impact us when trying to improve our website.

      * ##### **iii. Functional cookies**

These Cookies allow TeamViewer’s website to remember your preferences, such as your username, language settings, and/or the region you are in. These Cookies help to provide enhanced, more personal features. They can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customize or provide services you have asked for such as watching a video, using the chat functionality or commenting on a blog. These Cookies do not track your browsing activity across other websites.

      * ##### **iv. Marketing and Targeting Cookies**

These Cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns. These Cookies collect several pieces of information about your browsing habits. They are usually placed by advertising networks with our permission. They remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with other organizations, such as media publishers. These organizations do this in order to provide you with targeted adverts more relevant to you and your interests. This type of advertising is called online behavioral advertising. Furthermore, these Cookies allow us to analyze your website browsing behavior and thus allows us to customize our product marketing approach, e.g. help us decide on whether, when, and how to inform or get in touch with you based on your interests.

A full list of Cookies that TeamViewer uses can be found below in **Annex 1**.

  * ### **VI. Is personal data about you processed through Cookies?**

Not all Cookies collect and process personal data about you. Instead, anonymous data may be used in many cases. In certain instances, however, Cookies will help us and our partners to collect and process personal data through the use of Cookies. As far as your personal data is concerned, we would like to direct your attention to the respective descriptions in our privacy policies, in particular sections C.I.2., C.VI., D.VI., E.I.1., E.II.1., E.II.2., H., I of our General Privacy Policy and section 1.C.I. of our Product Privacy Policy. These will tell you more about the applicable categories of personal data and the purposes of the collection and processing that occur in this context. In general, it can be said that the data serves to provide the best possible experience to you when you use our websites and products and to further our business interest in monetizing our products. Please note that you can stop such collection and processing of personal data the same way you can stop the use of Cookies in general (see Cookie Settings).

  * ### **VII. Supplementary information**

We may embed external content from third party websites (e.g. Facebook, YouTube) within our website periodically. In addition to this, we sometimes partner with third parties who provide services for us which you can navigate to from our website. These third parties may use Cookies, you can find out about their approach to Cookies on their websites.

#### **ANNEX 1**

Here is the full list of cookies that are used on this website: **For TeamViewer AG:** TeamViewer AG only uses strictly necessary cookies to make sure that all website functionalities are running properly and there are no errors or interruptions while users are visiting our website. In particular, they are used for load balancing purposes as well as to record relevant session variables (such as disclaimer access). The cookies used are either session cookies or expire after 2 hours. Cookies used:

  * **IRPages2_Session**
  * **TS0157c0af**
  * **Laravel session**
  * **TS0157c0af**
  * **XSRF-TOKEN**

**For TeamViewer Germany GmbH**

## **TeamViewer Apps Privacy Policy**

**Introduction**  
We at TeamViewer Germany GmbH take protection of your personal data very seriously. Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, such as your name, address, email-addresses, IP address, or user behavior etc. The following policy provides you with information about the collection of personal data 1. in relation to the administration of the contractual relationship between you and TeamViewer Germany GmbH, and 2. your responsible use of the functionalities of our TeamViewer product, consisting of the Software as well as the Server Services as described and defined in the [End User License Agreement](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/eula/) (“ **EULA** ”) (hereinafter collectively referred to as (our) “ **Product** ”).

Below, we provide information about the collection and processing of personal data when using one of the TeamViewer mobile apps, including TeamViewer Host, TeamViewer QuickSupport and TeamViewer for Remote Control, TeamViewer Pilot, TeamViewer Meeting, Blizz (each referred to hereinafter as “ **App** ”).

**1\. Personal Data collected and processed under control of TeamViewer**  
A. Controller  
B. Data protection officer  
C. Categories of data  
D. Purpose and legal basis for processing  
E. Recipients  
F. Retention periods for personal data  
G. Statutory/contractual requirement  
H. Automatic decision-making  
I. Your rights

**2\. Information concerning your responsible use of the Product**  
A. Personal data processed through your use of the Product  
B. Data usage  
C. Data subjects rights

## **1\. Personal Data collected and processed under control of TeamViewer**

### **A. Controller**

TeamViewer Germany GmbH (“ **TeamViewer** ”), Jahnstraße 30, 73037 Göppingen, is controller pursuant to Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”) concerning any processing of personal data for which we determine the purpose and means of processing. For information on data processing for which we act as a processor on your behalf pursuant to Art. 4 para. 8 GDPR, i.e. in relation to your responsible use of the functionalities of our Product as described in the EULA, please refer to section 2. below.

### **B. Data protection  officer**

TeamViewer appointed Mrs. Hauser as external data protection officer, who can be reached at _[privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com)_ , at [KHauser@intersoft-consulting.de](mailto:KHauser@intersoft-consulting.de) or at intersoft consulting services AG, DSB TeamViewer, Dürer Str. 189, 50931 Cologne.

### **C. Categories of data**

#### **I. Download, installation, and setup of the Product**

By choosing to download our App from a third-party operated app store, necessary personal data are provided to that app store. This particularly concerns your **name/user name, email address, and ID** assigned to your app store account, **time of the download and your device ID**. The processing of your data through the operator of the App store is beyond TeamViewer’s control and we are not responsible for such processing. TeamViewer processes such personal data only insofar as it is necessary for the download to your mobile device.

When you install the Software and use the Product for the first time on a new device, we collect certain information from that device to ensure uniqueness. The specific information used will depend on the type of your device and platform operating system, but may include the **device type, device name, the IMEI, the MAC address and the mobile/cell phone number**. From this information, TeamViewer creates a unique **Machine ID** (MID), from which the TeamViewer master infrastructure generates the **TeamViewer Device ID** , which in turn allows it to distinguish between unique user devices that have the Software installed.

We will also ask you whether you use the Product (i) for private / non-commercial purposes, (ii) in a company / for commercial purposes, or (iii) for both, and your choice will be connected to the respective TeamViewer Device ID. We also collect and process information on the **type of license** (Freemium, trial, fee-based) under which you use the Product.

#### **II. Establishing a connection using the Product**

Whenever you run the TeamViewer Software client, the TeamViewer master server infrastructure will register whether the device is available for a connection session with other devices. To achieve that, TeamViewer collects and processes your **IP address, your location, TeamViewer Device ID, the Machine ID, and your chosen user screen name.** While trying to connect to another device, this data is exchanged between the TeamViewer master server infrastructure, selected TeamViewer routers, and the Software client of your envisaged connection partner. The decision on which connection paths are used, in particular which routing servers, depends on the analysis of this data, considering e.g. geography and current work load on individual routers. Once you successfully connect to another device and thus establish a remote control or other session with your connection partner, certain **Session Metadata** such as a **Session ID** , a **meeting ID,** and **the start and end times of your session** will be collected and processed.

#### **III. Signing up for a TeamViewer account**

When you sign up for a TeamViewer account, TeamViewer collects your  **name, email-address, a  password of your choice, along with time, date and time zone** of you signing in and creates a unique **TeamViewer Account ID** for your TeamViewer account.

#### **IV. Product usage data**

We collect and process information about **how you use  the Software and the Server Services**. This includes the **Session Metadata** mentioned above at 1.C.II., your **connection partners, which features of our Product you use** (including Remote Control, Chat, Video, and File Transfer), and **how frequently** you use them.

We may analyze this data together with information you submit to us, as further described under 1.D.IV. below as well as in our General Privacy Policy under sections C.VI.3. and D.VI.3.

#### **V. License auditing**

If you are using our Product under a Freemium Software license, we will analyze your **Product usage data** (see above 1.C.IV.) in accordance with section A./B.3.9 of the EULA to assess whether your usage pattern is in line with your indicated usage purpose and thus with the chosen license type. This assessment, which may also include an analysis of the **domain of an email-address** you have provided in the course of signing up for a TeamViewer account (see above!., will result in a “ **commercial score** ”. Depending on this score, we might suspect that a fee-based license, as opposed to a Freemium Software license, is required for your usage pattern of our Product, and we will inform you accordingly.

If you continue to use our Product in a way that indicates a violation of sections A./B.3.4 (Scope of use for the Freemium Software) and A./B.3.5 (Unauthorized Use) of the EULA, we may limit or ultimately block your access to the Server Services and ask you to purchase a fee-based license. In certain cases, this may involve an **automatic decision-making process** , where TeamViewer systems are configured to automatically put in place a limitation or even a blocking of your use of the Product.

If you think you are using our Product within the scope of the Freemium Software license, you may submit a corresponding request by way of our online form, for which we ask you to submit **your name, email-address, affected TeamViewer Device ID, and an explanation on your usage**. TeamViewer will then analyze your submission and again evaluate your detected usage patterns. In the course of the evaluation process, we may also ask you to submit a declaration confirming your use of our Product for private, non-commercial purposes only. For this declaration, we may ask you to submit **your name, postal address, explanation of your usage, and your signature**.

If you have indicated, at least partly, commercial purposes when installing the Software (see above, 1.C.III.) and do not decide to purchase a fee-based license after your free trial period expires, you may still want to continue using our Product as a Freemium Software user. In this case, you have to verify that you will be using our Product for private, non-commercial purposes only, by submitting your **TeamViewer Device ID, email-address, country, a description of your use of the Product, and log files from your device**. TeamViewer will analyze this information to determine whether the Freemium Software license is the correct license type for you.

#### **VI. Feedback**

When you provide feedback concerning your experience when using our Product, TeamViewer will collect and process **your TeamViewer Account ID (if you provide the feedback while logged-in), your country and language settings, as well as any information you submit in your inquiry (including attachments such as log files or screen shots), which may contain your email-address,  your name, company information, phone number, license key, or your TeamViewer Device ID.**

#### **VII. Support**

When you contact our support, we will collect your  **name, time and  date of your request, and your email-address**, if you contacted us via email, **or your  telephone number **if you contacted us via telephone, as well as the content of your request.

#### **VIII. Sending in-product messages**

TeamViewer may contact and inform you through in-product messages (using your **TeamViewer Device ID and, if you are a registered user, your TeamViewer Account ID** ) about changes to or improvements of our products, entirely new products, or to provide you with tips on how to best use our products as well as other useful information (e.g. on discounts, freebies or giveaways). In determining whether and how we contact and inform you, we may also process your **license type, language and version of the Product you use** , and/or your **country** , and we may also draw on data we have gathered through analyses and profiling measures as described in sections C.VI.  and D.VI. of our General Privacy Policy.

### **D. Purpose and legal  basis for processing**

#### **I.  ** **Download, installation, and setup of the Product**

When you install and setup our Product, TeamViewer processes your personal data to provide you with the option to use its functionalities. Legal basis to process your personal data as described under 1.C.I. is performance of our contract with you (i.e. the EULA) and thus Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

Regarding information on the purpose of marking your download copy of the Software with your Google Analytics Client ID, please refer to our General Privacy Policy, at sections D.VI.3.

#### **II. Establishing a connection using the Product**

Processing your personal data as described under 1.C.II. is necessary to provide you with the connection functionalities of our Product and thus to perform our contract with you (i.e. the EULA). The applicable legal basis is thus Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

#### **III. Signing up for a TeamViewer account**

When you sign up for a TeamViewer account, TeamViewer processes your personal data for the administration of the contract with you and to provide you with additional product functionalities. The legal basis to process your personal data as described under 1.C.III. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

#### **IV. Product usage data**

We strive to continuously improve the experience of using our Product. In order to do so, we need to better understand and categorize the needs of you, our users and customers. To achieve this, we may analyze how you use our Product as described under 1.C.IV. This way, we gather information that is required to improve and further develop our Product, e.g. to help us decide whether we should keep or amend functionalities the Product currently has or whether to create new features. We also evaluate your usage of the Product in order to recognize abusive or abnormal usage patterns and thus to help protect our network and service integrity at any time. Analyzing this information in this way is necessary to either perform our contract with you (i.e. the EULA) in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR and/or to fulfil our legitimate business interests pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

For more information on other purposes we also fulfil by processing Product usage data, namely to conduct license auditing and to gather information on whether and how to best contact and inform you, please refer to the respective sections below (1.D.V.) and in our General Privacy Policy (there at section D.VI.3.).

#### **V. License auditing**

TeamViewer processes information on how you use its Product in order to monitor and evaluate whether the agreed license restrictions are observed. Please note that, especially given the great number of (free) users of the Product, automated mechanisms such as limitations and ultimately blocking of suspicious usage are necessary to effectively monitor and enforce compliance with the licensing provisions of the EULA. Especially as the Freemium Software model is subsidized by the contributions of fee-based license customers, we have to make sure that everybody is using their licenses within the contractually agreed scope. Legal basis for processing your personal data as described under 1.C.V. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR and Art. 22 para. 2 lit. a) GDPR.

#### **VI. Feedback**

If you place an inquiry with TeamViewer by using the in-product feedback feature, TeamViewer processes your personal data in order to evaluate and possibly respond to your feedback. Legal basis for processing your personal data as described under 1.C.IV. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) and f) GDPR.

#### **VII. Support**

If you contact our support, TeamViewer processes your personal data in order to respond to your request. Legal basis for processing your personal data as described under 1.C.VII. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

#### **VIII. Sending in-product messages**

The data we process in order to decide whether and how to contact and inform you through in-product messages is required to perform our contract with you if you are using the Product under a Freemium Software license. Pursuant to section A./B.17. of the EULA, display and receipt of personalized marketing messages in the Software as well as the processing of personal data necessary to provide such personalization is a key element of our Freemium Software Product. The legal basis is thus Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

If you are using the Product under a fee-based license (other than Freemium Software), we will contact and inform you by way of in-product messages about our products and how you can use them most efficiently in order to meet our corresponding legitimate business interest. The legal basis is thus Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. You may choose to opt-out of receiving such messages by contacting privacy@teamviewer.com.

#### **IX. Other**

Where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to, we process your personal data pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c) GDPR.

### **E. Recipients**

TeamViewer has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure to third parties and to ensure that only relevant individuals, which act within their job description and have a need-to-know interest in accessing any of your personal data, will have access to the data for which they have sufficient clearance. This means, for example, that TeamViewer employees who conduct exercises of analyzing your usage behavior will, as a general rule, only receive pseudonymous data such as e.g. your TeamViewer Device ID, TeamViewer Account ID, or Session ID, rather than any data identifying you directly, such as your name or email-address. On the other hand, TeamViewer employees who administer and enhance the contractual relationship with you, will receive access to data identifying you by name, but will not necessarily gain access to profiling data.

We also use third-party service providers to help us operate our business and provide you the with the functionalities of our Product and serving your requests. This includes providers of connection routing services or IT operation and maintenance services, (cloud) storage service providers, and providers of (cloud) collaboration tools. These third-party providers may receive access to personal data through the service they provide. Examples include Anexia Internetdienstleistungs GmbH, Amazon Web Services, Box.com, or Microsoft (Dynamics 365, Azure).

TeamViewer chooses all third-party service providers with due care, obligates them to confidentiality, and concludes data processing agreements with them in accordance with the standards of the GDPR. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

Where TeamViewer transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have an adequate level of data protection recognized by the EU, for example to receive group internal IT services from Australia, the USA, and Armenia, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. In particular, we will conclude model contracts with corresponding entities and rely on the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework for certain transfers into the USA. Please refer to <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en> to obtain further information on the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established outside the EU or EEA, or to <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework> to obtain further information on the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

TeamViewer will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

### **F. Retention periods for personal  data**

TeamViewer retains your personal data for as long as is necessary according to the relevant legal basis for its processing. The exact retention period will thus depend on the categories of personal data and the processing purposes. Once this period has lapsed and a purpose for processing the data no longer exists, TeamViewer will delete the data.

### **G. Statutory/contractual requirement**

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to engage in a contractual relationship with us or receive adequate support.

### **H. Automatic decision-making**

Except as mentioned in 1.C.V. and 1.D.V. (License auditing), TeamViewer does not use your personal data for automatic decision-making that would produce legal effects or significantly affect you.

### **I. Your rights**

You may contact us either in writing or by email at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com) in order to exercise the following rights to the extent you are entitled to do so under applicable law:

  * You may access your personal data to check and review such data;
  * You may request a copy of your personal data;  
You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
  * You may object to the processing of your personal data (e.g. if we base our processing on legitimate interests (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR) or use your personal data for direct marketing purposes);
  * You may request to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and – subject to your acquisition of the respective copyrights or other required rights – have it transmitted to another controller, provided that the processing is based on your respective consent or to execute a contractual relationship or a relationship prior to entering into a contract with you.
  * You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data. In order to file a complaint, please contact the supervisory authority competent for your place of residency or alternatively, you may contact “Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit, Königstraße 10a, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany“.

Should you have any questions, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

### **2\. Information concerning your responsible use of the Product**

When you use our Product, we are providing it to you as a technical service that you may reasonably use. We technically assist you, as a data processor pursuant to Art. 4 para. 8 GDPR, with connecting to other devices, initiating meetings, the hosting of the contacts that you upload, or managing a team of people using our Product under your license. You are responsible for utilizing the Product in accordance with the applicable laws, including data protection laws. The particularities of tconchis relationship are defined in the [EULA](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/eula/), in particular in its section C. The following section of this Privacy Policy provides some additional explanations on how the Product works and what data is processed in this context on your behalf.

### **A. Personal data processed through your use of the Product**

In the following, we describe instances in which we are processing certain categories of personal data on your behalf when you use our Product.

#### **I.  Content data**

Any **content of screens, calls, and video transmissions, or actual files** that you exchange with anybody through our Product’s features and functionalities will be transmitted by TeamViewer using end-to-end encryption technology. This means that TeamViewer will not be aware of the content and subject matter of such exchanges. You, on the other hand, will have full access to this possibly personal and even sensitive data.

Our Product offers you the option to **share your screen** via the presentation, video call or phone call option. When you share your screen, please bear in mind that participants can see all items on your device.

The Product’s meeting functionality also enables you to be seen by other participants through your built-in device camera.

It is your responsibility to ensure that no rights of others are being infringed upon when such exchanges are initiated and conducted by you. Please bear this in mind, particularly when sharing information relating to persons not immediately involved in any current connection established through our Product (e.g. sensitive personal data on your device or the device of your connection partner that does not relate to either you or your connection partner).

#### **II. Scheduling and conducting a meeting**

While the content of any remote control sessions or meetings (such as presentations, video calls, and Voice over IP phone calls) will be transferred in an end-to-end-encrypted manner and thus generally not be visible for TeamViewer, we will still receive some metadata regarding your session such as any **meeting names** you use. If you use the “schedule meeting” function, TeamViewer processes additional personal data such as the  **subject of a meeting, time  **and, if you choose this option, **a meeting  password**.

#### **III. Log sessions reporting**

Our Product’s connection reporting feature will help you log and store connection metadata, including the **IP address, device name, display name, and  TeamViewer Device ID** for your connection partners. The log files including this personal data will be stored locally, i.e. on your device, and you can find the relevant path to the file through a link in the TeamViewer Software client. You may choose to deactivate this functionality, which is activated by default, by changing the options and preferences in the TeamViewer Software client.

#### **IV.  Session Recordings**

Our Product also gives you the option to **record and store content data** (see above 2.A.I.) in a location defined by you, such as a local or networked storage device. The Product will generally inform your session partners that a recording is being made and ask for their consent. Again, please make sure that such recordings do not infringe any rights of others.

#### **V.  Account data**

Our Product gives you the opportunity to store and share certain information within your TeamViewer account, such as your **email address** , a **user name** as well as a **display name** , your **language preferences** and **location**. You may also choose to edit your profile and upload a  **profile picture**. If you choose to upload a picture of yourself, please bear in mind that such picture is visible to your TeamViewer contacts. Please be aware that pictures may reveal your ethnic origin or health data, or may serve as biometric identifier, and consider the sensitivity of such data.

#### **VI.  ** **Buddy list, contacts**

Within your TeamViewer account, you may also create a **buddy list** containing information on **contacts** of yours. Please be mindful that contacts saved may contain data relating to persons who may not be aware that you saved them.

#### **VII. Data about employees or others using the Product under your license**

TeamViewer, as a data processor, will enable you to log and monitor connections and other activities conducted by employees or other persons using the Product under your license, in particular with regard to **account activities, recordings of sessions or connection metadata such as counterparts, start and end times, screen names** , etc. In your TeamViewer Management Console, you can activate and deactivate this feature and thus the described data processing for some or all of the accounts that are connected to your license, and you will be responsible for using these features in accordance with applicable laws, in particular data protection laws.

#### **VIII. Files and other content**

If you use TeamViewer to send files to other participants in a connection, the App will require access to files stored locally on the device. This may be configured using device settings to enable and disable such access. Any files are shared only between participants of a connection are not stored by TeamViewer.  
If you do not grant permission to access to the device folder, the App will not process the folder data. Please note that you may not be able to use this feature if you do not grant us permission to access the folder.

### **B. Data usage**

TeamViewer is using all of the personal data described in 2.A. above in order to provide you the functionalities of the Product as agreed in the EULA and the Order, and in accordance with the data processing provisions in the EULA, where additional information on security measures is available.

### **C. Data subjects rights**

Data subjects may exercise certain rights in relation to the processing of their personal data through the Product towards you. As your technical service provider, we may assist you to answer such requests as described in the data processing agreement in section C. of the EULA. Such rights may include accessing personal data, rectification, erasure, restriction of processing, data portability, and objection to the processing. Data subjects have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of their personal data.

Should you have any questions on the processing of personal data through TeamViewer, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

## **TeamViewer Privacy for TeamViewer Remote Management**

**Introduction**

We at TeamViewer Germany GmbH take protection of your personal data very seriously. Personal data means any information that can personally reference you, such as your name, address, email addresses, IP address, etc. The following policy provides you with information about the collection of personal data 1. in relation to the administration of the contractual relationship between you and TeamViewer Germany GmbH, and 2. your responsible use of the functionalities of TeamViewer Remote Management, consisting of the TeamViewer Monitoring & Asset Management, TeamViewer Endpoint Protection and TeamViewer Backup as well as the Server Services described in the EULA (hereinafter collectively referred to as “ **TeamViewer Remote Management** ”).

## 1\. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with TeamViewer

A. Controller respectively Provider  
B. Data Protection Officer  
C. Categories of Data  
D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing  
E. Recipients  
F. Retention Periods for Personal Data  
G. Statutory/contractual requirement  
H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling  
I. Your Rights

## 2\. Information concerning your responsible use of TeamViewer Remote Management

A. Personal Data processed through your use of TeamViewer Remote Management  
B. Data Usage  
C. Data Subjects Rights

## 1\. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with TeamViewer

### **A. Controller respectively Provider**

TeamViewer Germany GmbH, Jahnstraße 30, 73037 Göppingen (“ **TeamViewer** ”), is your contractual partner and controller of your personal data in accordance with Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”) and § 13 German Telemedia Act concerning the entering into and administering the contractual relationship with you. For information on data processing in relation to your responsible use of the functionalities of TeamViewer Remote Management as well as the Server Services as described in the EULA please refer to the information concerning the use of TeamViewer .

### **B. Data Protection Officer**

TeamViewer appointed Mrs. Hauser as external data protection officer, who can be reached at _[privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com)_ , at [KHauser@intersoft-consulting.de](mailto:KHauser@intersoft-consulting.de) or at intersoft consulting services AG, DSB TeamViewer, Dürer Str. 189, 50931 Cologne.

### **C. Categories of Data**

#### I. Use of TeamViewer Product:

With regard to personal information collected when you download and use our TeamViewer product, please refer to the TeamViewer product privacy policy.

#### II. Signing up for TeamViewer Remote Management:

When you sign up for TeamViewer Remote Management, TeamViewer collects your name, email address, a password of your choice, along with time, date and time zone of you signing in.

#### III. Download TeamViewer Remote Management:

When you download TeamViewer Remote Management to your computer, TeamViewer collects your IP address and name.

#### IV. License Auditing:

We will collect information about the frequency of your use of TeamViewer Remote Management.

### **D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing**

#### I. Download:

When you download TeamViewer Remote Management, TeamViewer processes your personal data to provide you with the option to use TeamViewer Remote Management. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined above under C. I. is a user agreement concerning the use of TeamViewer Remote Management, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

#### II. Signing up for TeamViewer Remote Management:

When you sign up to TeamViewer Remote Management, TeamViewer uses your personal data for the administration and enhancement of the contract with you. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined under C. II. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

#### III. License Auditing:

TeamViewer is using information about the frequency of your use of TeamViewer Remote Management in order to monitor if the agreed license restrictions are observed and in case we recognize that they are exceeded, we will contact you to suggest changing your license type. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. III is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR.

### **E. Recipients**

TeamViewer has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure and to ensure that only relevant individuals, which act within their job description and have a need to know interest in accessing personal data, will have access to your personal data. TeamViewer employees, who administer and enhance the contractual relationship with you will receive access to your personal data. If you have a paid subscription, employees who are concerned with processing such transactions will receive access to your data. In case you contact our support, our employees who are engaged in providing support will handle your personal data to the extent required to answer your request.

However, we also instruct third parties, such IT maintenance and storage service provider, to help us to operate our business. These third party providers may receive access to personal data through the service they provide. TeamViewer has chosen these third parties with due care and obligated them to confidentiality. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at privacy@teamviewer.com.

We will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

Where TeamViewer transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have an adequate level of data protection recognized by the EU, for example to receive group internal IT services from Australia, US and Armenia, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. Please refer to [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN) to obtain a copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established in third countries under Directive 95/46/EC, or to <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework> to obtain a copy of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

In the context of the provision of TeamViewer Remote Management, employees of TeamViewer’s affiliate Monitis LLC, located in Armenia (address: 9 Alek Manukyan St, Yerevan 0070, Armenia), may also have access to certain metadata and to data about the usage of the TeamViewer Remote Management for the purpose of performing analysis to improve and develop the TeamViewer Remote Management. Furthermore, employees from Monitis LLC may, in limited cases, provide you with support and thus receive access to your personal data. Additionally, employees of Hotjar Ltd, St Julians Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St Julians STJ 1000, Malta, may receive your personal data to analyze user behavior of TeamViewer Remote Management users.

### **F. Retention Periods for Personal Data**

TeamViewer retains your personal data for the duration of our contractual relationship with you, regardless if your subscription is for free or paid. Once this contractual relationship terminates, TeamViewer will delete your personal data, unless TeamViewer is legally obligated to retain personal data such as your name, your order form, and the date of the order, in accordance with § 257 German Commercial Code and/or § 147 German Tax Code for a minimum of six and a maximum of ten years, if you payed for TeamViewer. Personal data that we collect in order to carry out license auditing will be deleted three (3) months after the defined license auditing period has elapsed.

### **G. Statutory/contractual requirement**

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to engage in a contractual relationship with us or receive adequate support.

### **H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling**

TeamViewer does not use your personal data for automatic decision-making and profiling.

### **I. Your Rights**

You may contact us either in writing or by email at datarequest@teamviewer.com in order to exercise the following rights to the extent your entitled to so under applicable law:

  * You may access your personal data to check and review such data;
  * You may request a copy of your personal data;
  * You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
  * You may object to the processing of your personal data;
  * You may request to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and – subject to your acquisition of the respective copyrights or other required rights – have it transmitted to another controller, provided that the processing is based on your respective consent or to execute a contractual relationship or a relationship prior to entering into a contract with you.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data. In order to file a complaint, please contact the supervisory authority competent for your place of residency or alternatively, you may contact “Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit, Königstraße 10a, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany“.

Should you have any questions on the processing of your personal data by TeamViewer in relation to your contractual relationship, please contact privacy@teamviewer.com.

## 2\. Information concerning your responsible use of TeamViewer Remote Management

When you use TeamViewer Remote Management, we are providing the product to you as a technical service that you may reasonably use. We technically assist you, as a processor, with the use of the platform for your TeamViewer Remote Management devices. You are responsible for utilizing TeamViewer in accordance with the applicable laws, including data protection laws. The following section explains to you how TeamViewer Remote Management works.

### **A. Personal Data processed through your use of TeamViewer Remote Management**

TeamViewer Remote Management is a tool integrated in the TeamViewer product, with which you can monitor your IT infrastructure, such as hardware and software, keep your computers clean and save with anti-malware, and/or remotely restore and save your data to a cloud via disk to cloud backup. In order to use TeamViewer Remote Management, you must have subscribed to our TeamViewer product, as TeamViewer Remote Management is only available for in-product use.

While providing TeamViewer Remote Management, TeamViewer may receive personal data from the devices monitored. Depending on your usage of TeamViewer Remote Management, TeamViewer may receive different categories of personal data. However, due to end-to-end encryption, we are not able to access your content. The following paragraph outlines the categories of data processed.

**Monitoring** – provides checks on disk space, disk health, CPU usage, antivirus software, windows update, memory usage, Windows firewall, online state, event logs, windows service, processes online status, disk health memory It provides remote task management, alerts and email notifications.

**Asset Management** – creates an inventory of deployed hardware including type, name of hardware, descriptive text, vendor and software including version and modification date of installed and licensed components. Provides reporting functionality to cover hardware and software inventory. Personal information may be processed as part of collecting name of hardware. We recommend that hardware should be named anonymously or according to configuration item standards to ensure that personal information is not collected by TeamViewer Remote Management.

**Endpoint Protection** – provides real-time protection for files and automated scanning of devices such as removable media to identify potential threats. Personal information collected is limited to emails that are used to provide alerts and notifications of anti-malware scans.

**Backup** – provides functional to perform network backups controlled by backup policies, file selection and file exclusion, automatic deduplication, alerts for failed Backups and remote support through TeamViewer product. Backup functionality uses the Zoolz cloud service provided by Genie9 Ltd 32 Woodstock Grove Shepherds Bush London W12 8LE, United Kingdom with storage using Amazon Web Services located in Ireland.

Personal information may be contained within content subject to backup and restoration activities.

### **B. Data Usage**

TeamViewer is using all of the personal data described in section II. A. in order to provide you with the functionalities of TeamViewer Remote Management as agreed in the End User License Agreement and the Performance Specification and in accordance with the data processing provisions in section C. of the End User License Agreement where additional information on security measures is available.

TeamViewer Remote Management functionality supports remote management of devices across a network. The personal data processed when you use TeamViewer Remote Management is stored on servers hosted by Amazon Web Services in Ireland. We will not share personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

### **C. Data subjects Rights**

Data subjects may exercise certain rights in relation to the processing of their personal data through TeamViewer towards you. As your technical service provider we may assist you to answer such request as described in the data processing agreement in section C of the End User License Agreement. Such rights might be accessing personal data, rectification, erasure, restriction of processing, data portability and objection to the processing. Data subjects have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of their personal data.

Should you have any questions on the processing of personal data through TeamViewer, please contact privacy@teamviewer.com.
